Melanie Nicole Miller

901.236.4397 | 335 Throop Avenue, #2G, Brooklyn, NY 11221 melanie.n.miller@accenturefederal.com | http://www.linkedin.com/in/melanienmiller

SUMMARY

Tenacious analytical thinker with an uncompromising commitment to helping organizations accelerate business innovation through process-improvement strategies. Seasoned in methodical problem-solving with a solid understanding of the Software Development Life Cycle. Demonstrated experience utilizing a combination of business knowledge, technical skills, and strategic analysis to provide solutions, enhancements, and creative insights to critical functionality as a business analyst professional.

EXPERIENCE

Business Process Senior Analyst

Accenture Federal Services, Washington, DC

March 2014 – Present

- Aligned with the office of Federal Student Aid in the U.S. Department of Education federal diamond client as a functional technology/systems integration consultant with Public Trust 6c security clearance for the Application Delivery team.
- Mapped over 70 back end database fields using SQL queries and performed regression and assembly testing managing all tickets in JIRA on the conversion for 2 file loading processes from the IMS hierarchal database to the DB2 relational database.
- Documented requirements and led testing for the new user login on StudentLoans.gov and Teach-ATS.ed.gov from PIN to FSA ID resulting in the successful implementation of the new website entry process for over 40 million users with student loans.
- Served as an active member of the Accenture community as Community Service co-lead for the DC African American Employee Resource Group, spearheading monthly service projects, managing service hours for volunteers in the myCorporateCitizenship online portal, and establishing and maintaining relationships and partnership with local service organizations.

Business Analyst

Total Wine & More Corporate Headquarters, Potomac, MD

April 2013 – March 2014

- Conducted brainstorming sessions with stakeholders and subject matter experts (SMEs) to clarify, prioritize, and refine vision, scope, and requirements for large-scale projects designed to reduce costs and increase sales for the company.
- Leveraged Microsoft Visio to develop application prototypes and screen mock-up designs and led 2 User Acceptance Testing (UAT) training sessions as the SME of the mobile inventory tracking software application for a Motorola MC5590 device.
- Documented requirements and test cases for a Staging Folder export process allowing Point of Sales (POS) data integration with the newly implemented Customer Relationship Management (CRM) program for market research and customer loyalty.
- Wrote SQL queries in Microsoft SQL Server for data manipulations during quality assurance testing.

Custom Solutions Specialist

Total Wine & More Corporate Headquarters, Potomac, MD January 2012 – April 2013

- Interfaced with business users for the analysis, design, development, testing, and implementation of software applications.
- Gathered business requirements and converted them into functional specifications, user specifications, and test cases.
- Developed and presented a concise Business Process Flow diagram of the company's cost collection process, and updated macros using the Developer function in Excel for all cost collection templates to capture additional charges associated with item orders.
- Executed quality assurance testing and logged all bugs in Microsoft Visual Studio Team Foundation Server (TFS)
- Confidently transferred knowledge to production support team members prior to deployment of each software release.

Student Consultant

Hatch Early Childhood, Winston Salem, NC

July 2010 – April 2011

- Implemented business process re-engineering by leveraging the core competencies of a nationwide B-2-B vendor of cutting-edge technologies for the pre-K market with a 6-member project team of students with diverse and complementary skills.
- Utilized client-interfacing skills as the team's communications lead while project managing 2 transformational deliverables.
- Initiated an accurate needs analysis in order to assess resources and capabilities and executed extensive market research in developing a competitive analysis report to compare and evaluate the products and business models of the client's competitors.
- Designed and delivered innovative solutions to the client's sales territory model imbalance resulting in a talent management proposal that optimized employee placement in 39 states based on a data analysis using the Solver tool in Microsoft Excel.

EDUCATION

Wake Forest University Schools of Business, Winston-Salem, NC Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN

Master of Arts (Management) 2011 Bachelor of Arts (Political Science) 2009

SKILLS

- Productivity Software: Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Photoshop, Snagit, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Visio, Microsoft SharePoint, Microsoft Outlook, Lotus Notes, Open Office, WinZip, Websense, Remote Desktop
- Databases and Defect Tracking: Microsoft Access, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Visual Studio Team Foundation Server
- Languages: SQL, Java, JavaScript, HTML
- Operating Systems: Windows NT/2000/95/98/XP, Mac OSX and Linux